<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Collections on Open Terms Archive documentation</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/</link><description>Recent content in Collections on Open Terms Archive documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Metadata</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/metadata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/metadata/</guid><description>Collection metadata A collection is defined by the following metadata.
Required fields 🔗 Field Type Description name string Display name of the collection (max 3 words) id string Unique identifier derived from name (acronyms, dash-separated) tagline string Concise description of collection topic description string Detailed context beyond tagline languages Array of strings ISO 639 language codes allowed in collection jurisdictions Array of strings ISO 3166-2 country codes for covered jurisdictions Example:</description></item><item><title>Governance</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/governance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/governance/</guid><description>Collection governance Setting up and maintaining a collection needs fulfilling certain tasks. These tasks are handled through roles. Each of these roles can be volunteer or paid, and can be handled by one single or several different entities. The Open Terms Archive core team provides processes and tools to support all of these roles.
Host 🔗 This role ensures that a server and internet access is available to run the engine on and fetch the terms, either by using its own infrastructure or renting a server on a hosting provider.</description></item><item><title>Creating a collection</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/create/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/create/</guid><description>Creating a collection You are considering creating a new collection to track terms with Open Terms Archive? Amazing!
Define metadata 🔗 First of all, define the metadata of the collection you would like to create and keep them ready to be used when setting up the repositories.
Check existing collections 🔗 Now that you have a clear idea what you would like to track, double-check that there are no existing federated collections that you could contribute to.</description></item><item><title>Federation</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/federation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/federation/</guid><description>Federation Open Terms Archive is a decentralised system. It aims at enabling any entity set up their own collections and track terms on their own.
In order to maximise discoverability, collaboration and political power, public collections are federated within a single ecosystem. This makes their data mutually discoverable and enables mutualising effort.
Benefits 🔗 A collection that joins the federation enjoys the following benefits:
Visibility on the Open Terms Archive website lists of collections and datasets.</description></item></channel></rss>