<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Collections on Open Terms Archive documentation</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/</link><description>Recent content in Collections on Open Terms Archive documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating a collection</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/create/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/create/</guid><description>Creating a collection Define the necessary metadata First of all, define the metadata and governance of the collection.
Create repositories Declarations Create the collection declarations repository by using the demo-declarations repository as template:
Go to the demo-declarations repository Click on the “Use this template” dropdown and select “Create a new repository” Set the repository name to &amp;lt;collection_id&amp;gt;-declarations. For example: pga-declarations. When redirected to the newly generated repository, wait a minute or two for the automatic setup to run.</description></item><item><title>Governance</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/governance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/governance/</guid><description>Collection governance Setting up and maintaining a collection is done by fulfilling certain tasks. These tasks are handled through roles.
A curator, who decides what services and terms are welcome in the collection. A host, who ensures that a server is available. An administrator, who takes responsibility for ensuring that the engine and associated software tools are functional and up to date. Maintainers, who guarantee the quality of the tracked versions by reviewing contributions.</description></item><item><title>Metadata</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/metadata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/metadata/</guid><description>Collection metadata A collection is defined by the following metadata:
Concise description of the collection topic (examples: Largest global social media, Most used social media in France, Dating apps, Platforms providing services to businesses…). Collection name (3 words maximum, examples: Platform Governance Archive, France Élections, Dating, P2B Compliance Assessment…). Collection ID (examples: pga, France-elections, dating, p2b-compliance…). Terms language (examples: English, French, All EU languages…). Terms jurisdiction (examples: EU, France, EEA, USA, global…).</description></item></channel></rss>