<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Collections on Open Terms Archive documentation</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/</link><description>Recent content in Collections on Open Terms Archive documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Metadata</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/metadata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/metadata/</guid><description>Collection metadata A collection is defined by the following metadata.
Description A concise description of the collection topic.
Examples Largest global social media Most used social media in France Dating apps Platforms providing services to businesses Name Three words maximum.
Examples Platform Governance Archive France Élections Dating P2B Compliance Assessment ID An identifier derived from the collection name that can more easily be referenced in code. Use acronyms and replace spaces with dashes.</description></item><item><title>Governance</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/governance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/governance/</guid><description>Collection governance Setting up and maintaining a collection needs fulfilling certain tasks. These tasks are handled through roles. Each of these roles can be volunteer or paid, and can be handled by one single or several different entities. The Open Terms Archive core team provides processes and tools to support all of these roles.
Host This role ensures that a server and internet access is available to run the engine on and fetch the terms, either by using its own infrastructure or renting a server on a hosting provider.</description></item><item><title>Creating a collection</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/create/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/create/</guid><description>Creating a collection Define metadata First of all, define the metadata of the collection you would like to create.
Define governance Setting up and maintaining a collection over time needs fulfilling certain tasks on a regular basis. These tasks are handled through roles. To make sure that all these roles are covered, define the governance of your collection.
At any time, feel free to ask for help or partners in the community.</description></item><item><title>Federation</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/federation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/federation/</guid><description>Federation Open Terms Archive is a decentralised system. It aims at enabling any entity set up their own collections and track terms on their own.
In order to maximise discoverability, collaboration and political power, public collections are federated within a single ecosystem. This makes their data mutually discoverable and enables mutualising effort.
Benefits A collection that joins the federation enjoys the following benefits:
Visibility on the Open Terms Archive website lists of collections and datasets.</description></item></channel></rss>