<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Getting started on Open Terms Archive documentation</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/</link><description>Recent content in Getting started on Open Terms Archive documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Contributing terms</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/contributing-terms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/contributing-terms/</guid><description>Contributing terms Tracking new terms Tracking terms is done by declaring them and the service they are associated with. Such a declaration is achieved by editing JSON files in the declarations folder.
Before adding new terms, open the declarations folder and check if the service you want to track terms for is already declared. If a JSON file with the name of the service is already present, you can jump straight to declaring terms.</description></item><item><title>Declaring documents</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/guidelines/declaring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/guidelines/declaring/</guid><description>This document presents practical guidelines, is edited collaboratively and is not normative. Normative constraints are exposed in Contributing Terms.
Declaring documents Service name Casing In order to find the service name casing, rely first on the page title (easily found in search results). Do not rely on the logo as it can be stylized differently. Example with Facebook: If it is still ambiguous, rely on Wikipedia as a source. However, make sure to differentiate the service from the provider company&amp;rsquo;s name.</description></item><item><title>Explore a history of versions</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/how-to/navigate-history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/how-to/navigate-history/</guid><description>How to explore a history of versions Every public instance offers a public database of versions they recorded. For this guide, we will use the example of the Contrib instance. This instance publishes its history on the OpenTermsArchive/contrib-versions repository.
From the repository page, open the folder of the service of your choice. For example, WhatsApp.
You will see the set of documents tracked for that service, now click on the document of your choice.</description></item><item><title>Governance</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/governance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/governance/</guid><description>Governance Instances Creating an instance Each instance has an administrator who takes responsibility for ensuring that the engine is up to date and works properly, and maintainers who take responsibility for ensuring the quality of the resulting versions.
All of these roles can be either volunteer or funded by sponsors. Anyone is free to create their own collection using their own instance.
Referencing an instance A collection can be referenced in the Open Terms Archive federation if it abides by the following quality criteria:</description></item><item><title>Subscribe by RSS</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/how-to/subscribe-rss/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/how-to/subscribe-rss/</guid><description>Subscribe by RSS An RSS feed is a type of web page that contains information about the latest content published by a website, such as the date of publication and the address where you can view it. When this resource is updated, a feed reader app automatically notifies you and you can see the update. You can receive notification for a specific service or document by subscribing to RSS feeds.</description></item><item><title>Targeting</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/guidelines/targeting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/guidelines/targeting/</guid><description>What to track? Can I track terms that are not applicable yet? Yes.
For example, documents that would start applying at date in the future are legitimate candidates for tracking. You can this way track if their terms change even before they are applied.</description></item></channel></rss>