<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Getting started on Open Terms Archive documentation</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/</link><description>Recent content in Getting started on Open Terms Archive documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Metadata</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/metadata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/metadata/</guid><description>Collection metadata A collection is defined by the following metadata.
Description A concise description of the collection topic.
Examples Largest global social media Most used social media in France Dating apps Platforms providing services to businesses Name Three words maximum.
Examples Platform Governance Archive France Élections Dating P2B Compliance Assessment ID An identifier derived from the collection name that can more easily be referenced in code. Use acronyms and replace spaces with dashes.</description></item><item><title>Node</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/api/node/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/api/node/</guid><description>Node.js API [Beta] As a Node module dependency, the engine exposes a JavaScript API that can be called in your own code. The following modules are available.
fetch The fetch module gets the MIME type and content of a document from its URL
import fetch from &amp;#39;@opentermsarchive/engine/fetch&amp;#39;; Documentation on how to use fetch is provided as JSDoc.
Headless browser management If you pass the executeClientScripts option to fetch, a headless browser will be used to download and execute the page before serialising its DOM.</description></item><item><title>Browsing through terms</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/navigate-history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/navigate-history/</guid><description>Browsing through terms Every collection offers a public database of versions they recorded.
For this guide, we will use the example of the Demo collection. The terms of this collection are published on the OpenTermsArchive/demo-versions repository.
From the repository page, open the folder of the service of your choice by clicking on it. For example, GitHub:
You will see the set of terms tracked for that service, now click on the terms of your choice.</description></item><item><title>Collection</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/api/collection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/api/collection/</guid><description>Collection Web API [Beta] As Open Terms Archive is decentralised, each instance embarks its own API. The documentation relevant to the specific version of the engine on that instance is provided on that instance itself.
The Collection API exposes JSON data over HTTP. Its OpenAPI specification can be found at http://localhost:&amp;lt;port&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;basePath&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;API version&amp;gt;/docs.
That endpoint exposes both the OpenAPI specification if the requested Content-Type is JSON, and a Swagger UI for visual and interactive documentation otherwise.</description></item><item><title>Governance</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/governance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/governance/</guid><description>Collection governance Setting up and maintaining a collection needs fulfilling certain tasks. These tasks are handled through roles. Each of these roles can be volunteer or paid, and can be handled by one single or several different entities. The Open Terms Archive core team provides processes and tools to support all of these roles.
Host This role ensures that a server and internet access is available to run the engine on and fetch the terms, either by using its own infrastructure or renting a server on a hosting provider.</description></item><item><title>Creating a collection</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/create/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/create/</guid><description>Creating a collection You are considering creating a new collection to track terms with Open Terms Archive? Amazing!
Define metadata First of all, define the metadata of the collection you would like to create.
Check existing collections Now that you have a clear idea what you would like to track, double-check that there are no existing federated collections that you could contribute to. If you have a doubt about whether some terms you want to track would fit a collection, reach out to the collection maintainers.</description></item><item><title>Federation</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/api/federation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/api/federation/</guid><description>Federation API Open Terms Archive is a decentralised system that tracks collections of services&amp;rsquo; terms across multiple servers. Each collection operates its own API, and the Federation API unifies search and discovery across collections, fostering collaboration with external applications.
The Federation API exposes JSON data over HTTP. Its documentation is provided in a dedicated, interactive interface.
That endpoint exposes both the OpenAPI specification if the requested Content-Type is JSON, and a Swagger UI for visual and interactive documentation otherwise.</description></item><item><title>Subscribing to terms changes</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/subscribe-rss/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/subscribe-rss/</guid><description>Subscribing to terms changes An RSS feed is a type of web page that contains information about the latest content published by a website, such as the date of publication and the address where you can view it. When this resource is updated, a feed reader app automatically notifies you and you can see the update. You can receive notification for a specific service or document by subscribing to RSS feeds.</description></item><item><title>Contributing terms</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/contributing-terms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/contributing-terms/</guid><description>Contributing terms Tracking new terms Tracking terms is done by declaring them and the service they are associated with. Such a declaration is achieved by editing JSON files in the declarations folder.
Before adding new terms, open the declarations folder and check if the service you want to track terms for is already declared. If a JSON file with the name of the service is already present, you can jump straight to declaring terms.</description></item><item><title>Federation</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/federation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/collections/federation/</guid><description>Federation Open Terms Archive is a decentralised system. It aims at enabling any entity set up their own collections and track terms on their own.
In order to maximise discoverability, collaboration and political power, public collections are federated within a single ecosystem. This makes their data mutually discoverable and enables mutualising effort.
Benefits A collection that joins the federation enjoys the following benefits:
Visibility on the Open Terms Archive website lists of collections and datasets.</description></item><item><title>Design principles</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/design-principles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/design-principles/</guid><description>Design principles These overarching principles guide technical and governance decisions. They are fundamental and can only be changed through community consensus, based on a thorough impact assessment.
Each principle has a name, a rationale, and potential implementation examples or guidelines.
1. Never trust the services A major goal of Open Terms Archive is to enable assessing the loyalty of services towards their end users. Since loyalty is not assumed, trust can not be warranted.</description></item><item><title>Choosing selectors</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/guidelines/choosing-selectors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/guidelines/choosing-selectors/</guid><description>Choosing selectors Selectors are used in Open Terms Archive declarations to specify the parts of documents that should be recorded.
What are selectors Selectors are used in the select and remove keys of an Open Terms Archive declaration.
The “selectors” referred to are defined by the W3C Selectors standard, more commonly known as “CSS Selectors”.
An easy-to-read introduction to CSS Selectors can be found on mdn web docs.
Choosing durable selectors eases maintenance The design of web pages containing terms can evolve over time, leading to changes in their HTML (more precisely, to their DOM) which may render ineffective the selectors that were initially chosen.</description></item><item><title>Copywriting reference</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/memos/copywriting-reference/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/memos/copywriting-reference/</guid><description>Copywriting reference Each memo must be composed of the elements detailed below. You must follow this structure when writing your memos.
Title Write a short declarative sentence to highlight the key change. 140 characters maximum. Use the name of the service as the subject. Write in the present tense. Prefer active phrasings over passive (e.g., “Microsoft expands reach” rather than “Reach expanded by Microsoft“). Describe the policy change, not the name of the document.</description></item><item><title>Declaring documents</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/guidelines/declaring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/guidelines/declaring/</guid><description>This document presents practical guidelines, is edited collaboratively and is not normative. Normative constraints are exposed in Contributing Terms.
Declaring documents Service name Casing In order to find the service name casing, rely first on the page title (easily found in search results). Do not rely on the logo as it can be stylized differently. Example with Facebook: If it is still ambiguous, rely on Wikipedia as a source. However, make sure to differentiate the service from the provider company&amp;rsquo;s name.</description></item><item><title>How to publish a memo</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/memos/how-to-publish/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/memos/how-to-publish/</guid><description>How to publish a memo This guide will help you publish a memo on opentermsarchive.org/en/memos.
No technical skills are required.
Prerequisites A drafted memo compliant with the copywriting reference. 1. Send Send your memo to contact@opentermsarchive.org by writing it in the body of the email or as a file attachment. Feel free to add any comments or questions you may have about the content or format.
2. Review The Open Terms Archive core team will review your memo as quickly as possible.</description></item><item><title>Reviewing contributions</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/guidelines/reviewing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/guidelines/reviewing/</guid><description>Reviewing contributions Thank you for showing interest in reviewing contributions made to Open Terms Archive. This document is intended to help you get started and provide some guidelines for reviewing contributions.
Why is this important? We want to make sure that the contributions made to the project are of high quality and that they are in line with the vision of the project. We also want to make sure that the contributions are reviewed in a timely manner so that the contributors can get feedback and continue to contribute to the project.</description></item><item><title>Targeting</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/guidelines/targeting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/guidelines/targeting/</guid><description>What to track? Can I track terms that are not applicable yet? Yes.
For example, documents that would start applying at date in the future are legitimate candidates for tracking. You can this way track if their terms change even before they are applied.</description></item></channel></rss>