<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Terms on Open Terms Archive documentation</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/terms/</link><description>Recent content in Terms on Open Terms Archive documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/terms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to navigate history</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/terms/how-to-navigate-history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/terms/how-to-navigate-history/</guid><description>How to navigate history Screencast Learn how to navigate through versions history in this 4 minutes video, or scroll below for the textual version.
Manual Every collection offers a public database of versions they recorded.
For this guide, we will use the example of the Demo collection. The terms of this collection are published on the OpenTermsArchive/demo-versions repository.
From the repository page, open the folder of the service of your choice by clicking on it.</description></item><item><title>Tracking new terms</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/terms/tracking-new-terms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/terms/tracking-new-terms/</guid><description>Tracking new terms Tracking terms is done by declaring them and the service they are associated with. Such a declaration is achieved by editing JSON files in the declarations folder.
Before adding new terms, open the declarations folder and check if the service you want to track terms for is already declared. If a JSON file with the name of the service is already present, you can jump straight to the Terms reference.</description></item><item><title>Declarations maintenance</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/terms/declarations-maintenance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/terms/declarations-maintenance/</guid><description>Declarations maintenance All parts of a terms declaration (web location, selection, noise removal, distribution across multiple documents…) can change over time. The process of updating these elements to enable continued tracking is called maintenance. Without it, terms can become:
unreachable: no snapshot can be recorded at all, because the location changed or the service denies access; unextractable: no version can be extracted from the snapshot, because the selection of content or some filter fails; noisy: both snapshots and versions are recorded but the changes contain noise that should have been filtered out.</description></item><item><title>Reference</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/terms/reference/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/terms/reference/</guid><description>Terms reference Terms are declared in a service declaration file, under the documents property.
Most of the time, terms are written in only one source document (for example Facebook Terms of Service) but sometimes terms can be spread across multiple online source documents, and their combination constitutes the terms (for example Facebook Community Guidelines).
Source document The way in which a source document is obtained is defined in a JSON object:</description></item><item><title>How to add terms with the graphical contribution interface</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/terms/how-to-add-terms-using-with-the-graphical-contribution-interface/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/terms/how-to-add-terms-using-with-the-graphical-contribution-interface/</guid><description>How to add terms with the graphical contribution interface Screencast Learn how add terms with the graphical contribution interface in this 6 minutes video.
Manual Blank page when contacting support While using the graphical user interface for contribution, you may come across a blank page when trying to contact the team.
This may be caused by the lack of a mail program being set up in your browser.
Solution If you use Gmail, for example, these instructions explain how to add Gmail as the default mailto handler in Chrome.</description></item><item><title>How to be notified of terms changes</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/terms/how-to-be-notified-of-terms-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/terms/how-to-be-notified-of-terms-changes/</guid><description>How to be notified of terms changes An RSS feed is a type of web page that contains information about the latest content published by a website, such as the date of publication and the address where you can view it. When this resource is updated, a feed reader app automatically notifies you and you can see the update. You can receive notification for a specific service or document by subscribing to RSS feeds.</description></item></channel></rss>