<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>API on Open Terms Archive documentation</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/api/</link><description>Recent content in API on Open Terms Archive documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/api/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Node</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/api/node/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/api/node/</guid><description>Node.js API [Beta] As a Node module dependency, the engine exposes a JavaScript API that can be called in your own code. The following modules are available.
fetch The fetch module gets the MIME type and content of a document from its URL
import fetch from &amp;#39;@opentermsarchive/engine/fetch&amp;#39;; Documentation on how to use fetch is provided as JSDoc.
Headless browser management If you pass the executeClientScripts option to fetch, a headless browser will be used to download and execute the page before serialising its DOM.</description></item><item><title>Collection</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/api/collection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/api/collection/</guid><description>Collection Web API [Beta] As Open Terms Archive is decentralised, each instance embarks its own API. The documentation relevant to the specific version of the engine on that instance is provided on that instance itself.
The Collection API exposes JSON data over HTTP. Its OpenAPI specification can be found at http://localhost:&amp;lt;port&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;basePath&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;API version&amp;gt;/docs.
That endpoint exposes both the OpenAPI specification if the requested Content-Type is JSON, and a Swagger UI for visual and interactive documentation otherwise.</description></item><item><title>Federation</title><link>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/api/federation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.opentermsarchive.org/api/federation/</guid><description>Federation API Open Terms Archive is a decentralised system that tracks collections of services&amp;rsquo; terms across multiple servers. Each collection operates its own API, and the Federation API unifies search and discovery across collections, fostering collaboration with external applications.
The Federation API exposes JSON data over HTTP. Its documentation is provided in a dedicated, interactive interface.
That endpoint exposes both the OpenAPI specification if the requested Content-Type is JSON, and a Swagger UI for visual and interactive documentation otherwise.</description></item></channel></rss>